if you don't know how to play with time
frames you simply don't know how to
trade it doesn't matter if you're a day
trader scalper swing Trader you can't
properly top down analysis a chart you
cannot trade it doesn't matter what type
of Trader you are and if you want to be
able to be a sniper Trader and
constantly winning the markets and
become profitable you have to be able to
properly do a top down analysis in the
market so you can actually see what the
market is doing on different time frames
now before you become into a nerd or I
want to be expert on only one single
time frame I need you to realize that
there's not only one time frame to be
successful you need to be able to manage
multiple different time frames at the
same time and these are the main key
time frames that you need to know for a
top- down analysis that is going to be
the weekly time frame the daily time
frame and the 4H hour time frame does
not matter if you're a scalper day
trader swing Trader you need to have
these three main time frames in your top
down analysis so you can properly
understand the direction of the market
where it's headed and how you can find
an edge in the market so now let's get
into the video on how you can properly
do a top down analysis and I'm also
going to show you how to actually enter
a trade with my personal entry signal
that I use every single time I enter a
trade and it raises my win rate by even
20 to 25% so if you have a win rate of
40 to 50% if you just add this extra
entry stuff that I use you're going to
boost your win rate by 25 to 30% which
can lead you to about a 70% winning
strategy which is crazy so now let's
actually get into the markets right now
where I'm going to show show you how to
properly do a top- down analysis and you
can actually have an edge over the
market so let's get into it so first
things first is going to be the actual
time frames to do the top- down analysis
so there is hundreds of different time
frames you have the one minute the 2
minute the 3 minute 515 you have all
these different time frames you can
almost even create custom time frames of
your own liking which is actually you
know kind of bizarre doesn't even make
any sense in my opinion but the
possibility is there and then also you
can go down to the seconds and how many
seconds and stuff which is absolutely
just ridiculous you notice here I have a
star on every single time frame that I
personally use for every single time I
do a top down analysis on any pair on my
watch list so this does not matter the
currency pair that you're trading
doesn't matter if it's gbpusd Euro USD
GBP JPY the same top down analysis
applies to any pair any commodity any
future everything is exactly the same
because it just consists of a top- down
analysis the simple analogy that I can
put here is if you were to take a car
into a shop to do the oil change it has
to pass by the same exact inspection
they have to see how much oil is in it
how old is the oil in there how much how
many quarts of oil have to be added and
what type of oil it's the same thing
doesn't matter if it's a rollsroyce or
if it's a Honda Civic they have to go
through the same oil process to have the
standard of what they should do next
same thing here you have to go through
the standard of what the time frames are
doing to the determine if you're
interested in taking this trade so these
are going to be the main time frames
that I use which is the 15 minute 30 1
hour 2hour 4our daily weekly and monthly
so I put a star on them so they stay on
this top section here and I only focus
on the ones that are needed for a proper
top- down analysis so first things first
what is a top down analysis well it's
pretty self-explanatory you have to
start from the top down right it's a top
down analysis so you want to start off
from the highest of the time frame and
work all your way down so you were to
start off from the weekly then after the
weekly you would go to the Daily then
from the daily you would go to the 4
Hour the 4 Hour to 130 15 minutes it's
just pretty much a ladder that goes from
the highest time frame to the lowest
time frame but there's actually a very
specific way on how to do it and what
time frame do you divide from each don't
worry it's going to make sense and
literally just a second so for this
video we're going to be using the weekly
the daily the 4 Hour the 2 hour the 1
hour the 30 minute and the 15 minute so
this is actually divided right down the
middle almost pretty much and it's
divided right at this section right here
why you may ask well that is because the
weekly the daily and the 4our is used
for one parts of the top down analysis
and then the 2H hour the 1 hour and 15
and 30 minute is used for another part
of the top down analysis so this part is
going to be used for the trend to
identify if the market is headed to the
upside or the downside and then this
part right here which is the 2 hour the
1 hour the 30 and the 50 minute is going
to be used for the entry of the market
that you're going to be executing so you
have a top down analysis to identify the
trend and a top down analysis to
identify the entry which are is actually
very neat because this way you can
actually build an edge and make more
money so when you're doing a top 10
analysis you want to start off on the
weekly I have the monthly here I don't
use it as much anymore kind of just look
at every once in a while just to refresh
my memory from the beginning ways of my
strategy but I don't use it anymore to
be profitable haven't used it in a
really long time just have it there it's
kind of like a superstitious thing right
just I like it so you want to start off
on the weekly time frame so when you
start off on the weekly time frame in
the markets you're probably going to see
a market that looks something like this
you're going to see very big moves not
going to see a lot of rejections you're
not going to see a lot of movements it
just looks like one Big Blob of a move
simplest example I can show you is
actively what the market Has Done Right
Here looks like one Big Blob so if I
were to copy the most recent Market
structure it looks like one big move
like this very easy to identify not that
hard to pretty much see what's going on
right so this Market you can clearly
tell that it was going from bearish to
then bullish and that this Market has
shifted completely at at this section
right here let me actually just delete
this stuff so you can see how this
Market has gone from bearish to then
bullish this Market was creating lower
lows and lower highs and then we broke
this structure level making this a new
higher high now we I understand by doing
a top down analysis that the weekly time
frame is bullish so it's going to look
something like this now when we do a top
down analysis all we're doing is
literally zooming in to the exact same
price that you are seeing right here so
this same exact move that we have
identified on the weekly time frame that
has shifted structure when we go to the
Daily time frame all we literally do is
just zoom in all we do is get a little
bit closer and when we get a little bit
closer what happens we start seeing a
little bit more of the detail of what's
going on in the market so this exact
same Market move is what's going on
right here and I'm just going to go down
to the Daily because I've already done
the top parts of the analysis now I'm
going to start working my way down and
when I started from the top I realized
that this Market is now going to the
upside or this Market is going to the
downside whatever the case is then I go
down to the Daily time frame and I
notice that within this same exact
Market move there is a lot of structure
that is happening inside here so all I'm
simply going to do is just draw out the
structure points following the same
weekly move that happened on the section
to the upside so if you notice this is
the same exact move from right here on
the weekly but now this is on the daily
so we can identify from a top down
analysis why it's so important on doing
it because if we were to only look on
the daily this is what we would see and
we would see a bunch of rubbish we would
see literally the market going up down
up down up down it's a bit confusing but
then if we look at the weekly we get a
very clear indication of where the
masses of the markets are actually
heading and this is actually very key
because you could only focus on what
matters do you want to only take a day
trade do you want to take an overall of
a swing trade do you want to take a
little scalp trade this is very
important because you can almost do a
little bit of everything with the proper
top- down analysis confirmation because
if you were to look at this on the
weekly you would want to pretty much buy
because this time frame is currently
bullish but then if you were to look at
this time frame you would tell that it
is bearish even though it's a probably a
beginner Trader this might look bullish
it's actually bearish you can see how
the market was here indeed creating
higher highs higher lows higher highs
higher lows higher highs higher lows
higher highs and then we had broken this
previous higher low making this market
now bearish so we've identified that the
daily time time frame is now shifting to
the downside and this can kind of make a
little bit of sense because for the
weekly time frame what this can create
is an even deeper pullback so then the
weekly time frame can continue going to
the upside hypothetically but we know
that the weekly could have that deeper
pullback because the daily time frame is
now bearish and it's simply going
bearish to give this weekly time frame
the deeper pullback so then it can have
the push to the upside so they're both
both doing the same move but one's just
pretty much taking the hit for the other
one to have the actual move overall but
this is all big hypothetical right this
is uh basically what we're having right
in front of us right now and it is 100%
a fact and that is that the weekly time
frame is a bullish and then that the
daily time frame is bearish so as we're
going through this top 10 analysis we're
like well does it make more sense to buy
or does it make more sense to sell but
as of right now we have a 50/50 can't
really get a clear indication it's why
we have to go down now to the 4 4 hour
so we're simply going to get the same
exact Market move from the daily time
frame right here we're going to put it
right back into place just so we can
pretty much confirm that all we are
doing is just zooming in so we all agree
that this is the market structure there
now we go down to the 4 Hour so we
already started from the top and we're
working our way down now this is
currently how this looks on the 4our
time frame so for examples purposes I'm
going to Simply start it off from this
point right here just because there's a
lot of Market structure and I can pretty
much be all night identifying every
single one of these structure points so
just going to follow every single higher
low and higher high that this Market
created along the way of it heading to
the upside and every lower lower and
lower high that this Market created
heading to the downside so as you guys
can see it might look a little bit messy
but once I move it to the outside you
can see very clearly right here that
came out from that 4H hour section and
that this right here is the original
daily structure move so we making this
very very simple very very
straightforward this is what the top-
down analysis looks like on the weekly
time frame this is what the top down
analysis looks like on the daily time
frame and now this is what the top down
analysis looks like on the 4-Hour time
frame everything you're seeing here is
the exact same markets as as you can
tell it's been GBP USD the whole entire
way the only thing that has changed is
that we have gotten in closer and closer
and closer to identify what makes more
sense does it make more sense to buy or
does it make more sense to sell because
at the end of the day the Market's going
to do two things it's either going to go
up or it's going to go down we're simply
trying to find an edge on where it makes
the most sense that the Market's going
to go and as of right now that we've
identified the weekly time frame as
bullish and we've identified the daily
time time frame as bearish we can
confirm that the 4-Hour time frame is
also bearish why maybe it's a beginner
Trader you can identify this as bullish
but it's actually the same exact concept
as the daily time frame this Market was
creating beautiful higher lows and
higher highs heading to the upside but
then this was the last higher low broke
under that structure level making the
4-Hour time frame now bearish so as you
can see this is the move that fits
perfectly inside here and this is the
move that perfectly fits inside of this
Market structure right here so every
single time frame that we go down we
just get more in detail on what the hell
the market is doing exactly this way we
can find an edge on what decision should
we take So based off of this right here
off of creating a top 10 analysis my
bias is already making more sense to
enter a sell than to enter a buy why
because as I started started from the
top and I started working my way down
with the top down analysis it's clearly
that two time frames are going beish
versus one time frame is bullish so as
of right now that is literally only the
first half of top down analysis which is
going to be the weekly the daily and the
4our this is to Simply understand the
trend of the market where is the
majority of the time frames headed so we
can pretty much create an edge on that
direction and take the trade that way
now this is what I do do personally for
myself to catch day trades intraday
trades and also swing trades some of you
scalpers out there people that are
taking even you know trade on the lower
time frames you guys don't have to start
on the weekly you guys can pretty much
go Daily 4 Hour 2 hour and then you look
for your entries from the D from the
lower time frames down I personally like
the weekly the daily and the 4 Hour
simply because the higher time frames
are more respected than the lower time
frames why well it's because it takes
the weekly a lot more time to create a
structure Point than it does on the 1
hour in order for the 1 hour to create a
structure Point can literally happen
within four to 5 hours which happens
very often but on the weekly time frame
for it to create a structure point it
takes about four to 5 weeks to create
the same structure point so what do you
think is going to have a stronger basis
of holding price something that happens
every four or five hours and can happen
tens of times throughout the day or or
do you think something that happens once
every month to month and a half it's
pretty logical in my opinion it's why I
stick to the stronger because at the end
of the day I want to put my money behind
something that is going to give me more
odds of making me money versus not just
doesn't make you know sense in my mind
so after we understand that this is the
top down analysis for the trend of the
market now we're going to go through the
top down analysis of the entry part
which is very key because it's where a
lot of Traders pretty much just want to
jump the gun and go straight into
entering the market but they got to
understand that before entering the
market they have to properly do a top
down analysis to actually be able to
execute a trade so now that we
understand that two of these time frames
are bearish I'm just going to remove the
one that's bullish because we're not
interested in buying at all and we
should not be interested in buying at
all we don't want to take a counter
Trend trade makes no sense it's a
high-risk trade so we're going to only
look for reasons to sell so now that we
have our two time frames that are going
to confirm to us that this is bearish
we're going to now look for entries on
the 2H hour the 1 hour the 30 minute and
the 50 minute so what exactly are we
looking for on these time frames in
order to take the trade now this is
literally where you're about to have a
aha moment you're literally about to
tell yourself wow I cannot believe that
I have not been seeing this so like I
like it's literally like been right in
front of your face the whole entire time
and that is if we are
selling why don't we continue the
selling top down analysis Market
structure on the entry points what does
that mean let me show you so if we are
interested in selling this market right
here we know that this is what it looks
like from the daily to the 4our here now
this exact same Market structure let's
say hypothetically on the 30 minutes
just to show you guys very simply with
the same exact Market that we're
currently using you can see that on the
30 minute it's going to look very very
different let me just bring this here
put it back on where the market is so we
know that we're exactly on the same
Market that we drew up in this section
right here now this just back on this
area so let's look at it on the 30
minutes so if we go on the 30 minute
time frame you can see how we're just
going to structure up this last section
here you can see how it consists of a
lot more structure points literally
creating a bunch of little higher lows
and higher highs throughout the whole
entire way and this is obviously
happening a lot faster than the 4-Hour
time frame then the daily time frame so
on and so forth so if you notice right
here this markets on the 30 minute time
frame looks very different than you
would want it to now what do I mean by
that it's very confusing well don't
worry it's about to make a lot of sense
right now so I'm just pretty much
dragging this all the way back to our
4our section which is going to be right
around over here so what I have done
right here is I've literally brought in
this zoomed in section of the entry area
of gbpusd on the 30 minutes from the 4H
hour so this is the 4H hour time frame
now this is what it looks like on the 30
minute time frame so I've obviously only
focused on this section here because if
I were to pretty much go back all this
would look very rubbish it would have a
lot of different structure points and
doesn't matter to what we're about to do
right now so if this is what the 4H hour
time frame looks like and we've
understood that this time frame is
bearish just going to put it here so
it's very Visual and this is what the 30
minute time frame looks like what is
this 30 minute time frame doing right
now are we actively bullish or are we
actively bearish well once again
probably to a begin a Trader this time
frame might be bearish but they're
actually wrong this time frame is
bullish this Market was creating lower
lows lower highs lower lows lower highs
lower lows lower highs lower lows and we
have now shifted to the upside making
this 30 minute time frame bullish so now
that this 30 minute time frame is
bullish well doesn't mean that it's the
right time to enter this trade because
we are looking to sell and we can only
sell when we have a bearish market if we
have a lower time frame which is the
time frame that we're going to enter
that is against our overall topown
analysis Trend it simply does not make
sense to enter the trade the lower time
frames have not shifted the structure
yet making it not logical to enter the
trade so this right here would be a
perfect example of a loss that a Trader
would take or a position that I
personally would avoid so to make this
very simple and very straight to the
point it simply comes down to this if
this is going to be let's say the 4our
time frame and this is what the market
would look like on the 4H hour and if I
were to divide it from 4 hour to then 30
minutes this is what it would look like
on the 30 minute let me just make it a
very clear cut through version of what
it could look like following the same
path this is simply going from the 4H
hour to the 30 minute time frame they're
obviously exactly the same this is
simply just 4 hour and then this is
going to be 30
minutes we are analyzing this Market
looking to take this trade to the upside
this is where we would wait for this
pull back here to then buy this is going
to be the key of a patient Trader
waiting for this area to hit to then
enter the position now this is where top
down analysis is so crucial because this
pullback right here is going to give you
the perfect confirmation that you have
to wait why because now this time frame
has gone bearish all the way up to this
area in here and you cannot enter this
Market as long as this Market continues
bearish you could only enter on this
Market once it has shifted with the
overall time frames from the top that
analysis
if the 4our and then the daily time
frame are bullish you want to make sure
that then the 30 minute time frame is
also bullish with the overall time
frames on the pullback it went bearish
and then we have to wait for it to
Simply go bullish so we can then
continue to take this trade to the
upside the key is when you're going to
enter the trade on the lower time frames
you want to make sure that it allow
aligns with the trend of the overall top
down analysis if you were to write down
one thing from this one entire video
that would be it right there so pause
the video watch it and as you pause the
video hit that subscribe button because
this right here took me like 2 and
1 half years to understand and the fact
that I'm just putting it in this video
right now is actually crazy so hit that
subscribe button right now cuz nobody
else is making it as simple and as
effective as I am right now because this
alone can boost your win rate by 25 to
to 30% so make sure you hit that
subscribe button so this obviously looks
very simple on line chart right but we
don't trade line charts we trade
candlesticks let me actually show you
how it looks like on the Candlestick
section so I'm just going to pretty much
hold on to this for just a quick second
I'm going to show you guys on this very
live example that I'm actually very
eager to enter right now so as you guys
can see this is a very clear shift of
structure if we were to start off from
the daily time frame well let's start
off from the weekly right weekly we can
very clearly tell that we have had a
lower low lower high lower low now we've
had a higher high weekly time frame is
actually bullish but you can see how we
have very strong weekly rejection
candlesticks confirming to us that this
can pretty much not like this area and
have a deeper pull back to then continue
to head to the upside because the
overall trend is bullish on the weekly
time frame now starting from the top
working our way down to the Daily time
frame you can see that the daily time
frame has actually shifted structure
beautifully you can see how we have a
very valid left head and then a right
shoulder we have confirmed broken
through the neckline of that Head and
Shoulder well now this time frame is
bearish so we have two completely
different time frames telling us two
completely different things it's 50/50
you want to go with the weekly 50% of
going up you want to go with the daily
50% chance of going down well I'm not
going to take a trade on a 50/50 chance
I want to have the majority of the
possibilities that I can in order to T
enter this trade that's why I'm going to
go down now to the 4H hour to continue
this top down analysis when I come over
to the 4our I can very clearly tell that
this 4our was in a bullish trajectory
heading to the upside creating higher
highs and higher lows and then we had
this massive bearish move that has
engulfed pretty much the last couple of
weeks in one single session what it did
indicating to us that well now now the
4our is bearish as well giving us two
time frames that are bearish versus one
now I want you to ask yourself what
makes more sense to sell or to buy
obviously to sell so now we move over to
the entry part of the actual trade so
you can go to the 2hour the 1 hour the
30 minute the 50 minute whatever looks
cleaner I like the 30 minute the most
out of anything so when I go over to the
30 minutes you guys can see here that in
the 30 minutes we have structure
everywhere we have structure here
heading to the upside then we have
structure here heading to the downside
and on this structure heading to the
downside we can see how we created a
insane amount of a double bottom and
then we have now shifted to the upside
making the 30 minute time frame bullish
you cannot enter a sell if you have a
bullish time frame what do you have to
do you have to wait for this time frame
to now go bearish and once it goes
bearish then you can continue to take
the trade with the overall market now I
don't think you guys understand how
powerful this is this is literally the
market showing you its hand first so you
can then follow it a lot of Traders want
to predict the Market's hand before it
actually happens not me I want the
market to show me what it's going to do
after it shows me what it's going to do
I'm like all right cool you're actually
going to go down well I'll jump in with
you I don't want to predict that it's
going to go down I want to wait for for
it to confirm that it's going to
continue going down with these other
time frames so then I can actually then
jump on the ship with it it's almost
like a hack it's literally telling you
hey I'm actually going to start going
down to the downside now the lower time
frames are pretty much letting you know
that so when you get over to the 4H hour
time frame you were to pretty much see
one big red Candlestick going like this
and what you know is that on the 30
minute time frame we shifted this is
where you enter the trade and then you
can pretty much set and forget your way
to success because the lower time frame
is confirming that it is going to
continue the trend with the top analysis
of the overall time frames and you're
probably asking yourself what is this
word set and forget and how can you set
and forget your way to success like is
that even possible well that's what my
students have been doing in the last
three months they've been making
anywhere from ,000 to
$1,500 a week as a beginner set and
forget Trader where they're literally
catching trades like this with me every
single week on a call that I get with
them and I explain to them my top two
top three pairs that I trade for the
week that have the clearest and most
precise top down analysis that give us
the edge on the market and confirm to us
that hey it makes more sense to sell at
this moment than to buy simply because
the overall time frames are actually
going down just hop onto the trend to
the downside or all the time frames are
going up hop on the trend to the upside
and if you don't know what set and
forget is and you want to know more
about it well make sure you hit the link
in the description below I have a video
there for you that explains to you
exactly what s forget is and how it's
changed lives all around the world and
it lets Traders make anywhere from a
th000 to
$1,500 a week as a beginner set foret
Trader so make sure you guys watch that
video the link is in the description
below I appreciate you guys watching
this video all the way to the end if you
want to see more videos like this make
sure you hit that like And subscribe
button and I actually have a video for
you that explains to you precisely on
what candlesticks are so make sure you
check it out in this section right here
and I'll see you guys in the next video
take it EAS you guys